我刚看过了
Okay, I checked.
我们有伯爵茶  英式早餐  肉桂棒
We have Earl Grey, English Breakfast, Cinnamon Stick...
菊花茶  薄荷茶  黑莓还有
...Chamomile, Mint Medley, Blackberry and
等着  还有一样  柠檬茶
Wait, there's one more. Lemon Soother!
你不是那个要喝茶的人对吧
You're not the guy that asked for tea, are you?
有信来  瑞秋·格林  七号间
Mail call! Rachel Greene, bunk seven.
谢谢
Thank you.
酷  免费试喝的咖啡
Oh, cool! A free sample of coffee.
太好了  不然没处喝咖啡是吧
Oh, good. Because where else would we get any?
说的也对
Oh, right.
-这下好  -那是什么
- Oh, great. - What is it?
乡村俱乐部的每日公报
Country club newsletter.
我妈给我寄来订婚公告暗示我找男朋友
My mother sends me the engagement notices for inspiration.
我的天  是巴瑞和明蒂
Oh, my God! It's Barry and Mindy!
-巴瑞  你差点跟他...  -就是他
- Barry, who you almost - Barry, who you almost
-明蒂  你的前伴娘...  -就是她
- And Mindy, your maid of - Mindy, your maid of
我看看  那是明蒂吗
Let me see. That's Mindy?
真漂亮!
She is pretty!
真幸运...
Lucky...
有你这样的朋友
...to have had a friend like you.
马塞尔  拿饭给我  快
Marcel, bring me the rice. Come on.
好小子  把饭给我
Good boy. Give me the rice.
真乖  谢谢
Thank you. Good boy.
他终于能分辨"拿来"和"尿在"的差别了
He's mastered the difference between "bring me the" and "pee in the."
给我拿来...瑞秋你怎么了
"Bring me the" and Rach?
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我真是太傻了
This is so stupid!
是我不要巴瑞的  对吧
I mean, I gave Barry up, right?
我应该为他们高兴
I should be happy for them.
我...真为他们高兴
I am. I'm happy for them.
-真的吗  -不
- Really? - No.
如果我现在有男友也许就大不同了
I guess it would be different if I were with somebody.
哇哦  什么
Whoa, what....
你不是说"不谈感情  受够了男人"
What happened to "Forget relationships! I'm done with men!"
带把儿的全面封杀吗
The whole penis embargo?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想跟有没有男人无关
I guess it's not about no guys.
而是没有遇到对的人
It's about the right guy, you know?
和巴瑞在一起轻松自在  但是没有激情
With Barry it was safe and easy, but there was no heat.
和保罗在一起就充满激情
With Paolo, all there was, was heat.
-如野兽般原始的性爱  -行了我懂
- lt was this raw, animal, sexual - Right. I got it.
我能体会
I was there.
你认为我能两者同时拥有吗
Do you think you can have both?
一个既能当知己  又能给我激情的人
Someone who's your best friend but also can make your toes curl.
是呀
Yes.
我认为能  真的
Yes, I do. I really do.
其实说来好笑
In fact, it's funny.
通常你认为不可能让你
Often, someone you wouldn't think could...
感受到激情的人
...curl your toes...
却可能是
... might just be the one who...
被打断了
...gets interrupted.
回来啦  电影如何
Guys. How was the movie?
-棒极了  -很不错
- Wonderful! - So good!
-逊毙了  -根本是小妞们看的嘛
- Suck fest. - Total chick flick.
真遗憾这不是那种枪林弹雨
I'm sorry it wasn't one of those movies with guns and bombs...
公车飞飚的电影
...and buses going really fast!
电影暴不暴力无所谓
I don't need violence in a movie...
只要有裸体镜头我就满足了
...as long as there's a little nudity.
-那电影也有裸体镜头  -我是指女生的
- There was nudity. - I meant female nudity.
谁要看卢·格兰特的激情戏
I don't need to see Lou Grant frolicking.
是休·格兰特
Hugh! Hugh Grant!
行了  我得走了
All right, I've got to go.
走吧  马塞尔  快
Come on, Marcel, come on.
我们去洗澡  对不对  洗澡澡
We're gonna go take a bath. Yes,we are, aren't we?
他们只是朋友对吧
They're still just friends, right?
明天见
And I will see you tomorrow.
对  你明天要跟瑞秋阿姨待在一起
That's right. You're gonna spend tomorrow at Aunt Rachel's.
等等  莫妮卡阿姨对此事有发言权吗
Hung on, hung on. Does Aunt Monica get a say in this?
莫妮卡阿姨  请说吧
Please, Aunt Monica, please?
拉倒吧  你又不在这儿
Unclench. You're not even gonna be here.
我无法相信我们竟在讨论此事
I can't believe we're discussing this.
我同意  我也无法相信
I agree. I'm, like, in disbelief.
你不觉得  如果你和瑞秋来电的话
I mean, don't you think if things were gonna happen with Rachel
怎么会拖到现在
they would've happened already?
听我说  她说她希望能找到我这样的人
I'm telling you, she said she's looking for a relationship
当她的男友
with someone exactly like me.
她真的这样说
She said that?
"我这样的"是我自己加的
Well, I added the 'exactly like me' part...
她说她在寻找真命天子
But she said she's looking for someone.
而此人今晚就会出现
And someone is gonna be there tonight.
今天晚上吗
"Tonight" tonight?
这样最好不过了  因为只有我们两个
I think it's perfect. You know, it'll just be the two of us.
她整天都在照顾我的猴子
She spent all day taking care of my monkey.
我都忘了上次有女人
I can't remember the last time
照顾我的"猴子"是啥时候了
a girl took care of my monkey.
总之  下班后  我要去买瓶酒…
Anyway, I figured after work, I'd pick up a bottle of wine...
去向她"示爱"
...go over there and try to woo her.
知道你该怎么做吗
Know what you should do?
带她回到还用"示爱"这个词的
Take her back to the 1890s
十九世纪90年代去
when that phrase was last used.
如果你继续这样  宝贝  我发誓
If you keep this up, honey, I swear
这星期内你就可以和这个浑蛋了结
you'll be finished with this sucker by the weekend.
围羽毛围巾的是弗兰西斯博土
The one in the feathered boa is Dr. Francis.
她曾是个男人
Now, she used to be a man.
快看  蕾文出现了
Okay, now look, see, there's Raven..
我们讨厌她  真高兴她就快死了
We hate her. We're glad she's dying.
什么  马塞尔
And then What? Marcel!
你在玩莫妮卡的鞋吗  你不能...
Are you playing with Monica's shoes? You're not supposed to
马塞尔  你在鞋里大便吗
Marcel, did you poo in the shoe?
天啊  马塞尔  坏猴子
Oh, Marcel! Bad monkey!
天哪
Oh, God!
抱歉  巴瑞
Sorry, Barry.
一份小小的订婚礼物
A little engagement gift.
我相信你没预订这个
I'm sure you didn't register for that.
谁死了  谁死了
Who died? Who died?
翻过去  好不好  翻过去
Roll him over! Come on, roll him over!
好吧  我们知道不是德斯勒
Well, we know it wasn't Dexter,
对不对  马塞尔  因为...
right, Marcel? Because
马塞尔
Marcel?
-你怎会把他弄丢了呢  -天晓得
- How could you lose him? - I don't know!
我们在看电视  他在莫妮卡的鞋内大便
We were watching TV, he pooped in Monica's shoe....
等等  他在我的鞋里大便  哪个
Wait. He pooped in my shoe? Which one?
我不知道  左脚
I don't know. The left one!
是哪一双
Which ones?
那双你觉得配什么都好看的厚底门诺鞋
Those little clunky Amish things you think go with everything.
为何一片愁云惨雾
Why is the air in here so negative?
瑞秋把马塞尔弄丢了
Rachel lost Marcel.
不会吧  怎么丢的
Oh, no! How?
-他在我鞋里大便  -哪个
- He pooped in my shoe. - Which one?
我常穿的那双可爱黑鞋
The cute black ones I always wear.
不  是哪一只
No, which one?
左脚还是右脚
The right or left?
因为左脚表示幸运
Because the left one is lucky.
大家快想办法  我们该怎么办
C'mon, you guys, what're we gonna do, what're we gonna do?
有了  如果你是只猴子  在大城市迷路
All right. You're a monkey. You're loose in the city.
你会去哪儿
Where do you go?
这是他第一次出门
It's his first time out,
所以大概会走游览路线
so he probably wanna do some touristy things.
我去上演《猫》的地方找
I'll go to Cats.
你去俄罗斯茶室
You go to the Russian Tea Room.
我的天  别再闹了
Oh, my God! Come on, you guys!
他马上就会回家  他不会饶过我的
He'll be home any minute. He's gonna kill me!
这样  我们从楼内搜起
Okay, we'll start with the building.
你们找一楼二楼
You guys take the first and second floor,
菲比和我找三楼四楼
Phoebe and I'll take third and fourth.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
你留在家里等电话
You stay here and wait by the phone.
往我鞋内喷消毒水
Spray Lysol in my shoe
顺便等罗斯回来宰了你
and wait for Ross to kill you.
有人要交换吗
Does anybody want to trade?
干嘛
What do you want?
哈克斯先生  我们的朋友丢了只猴子
Mr. Heckles, our friend lost a monkey.
你有看到吗
Have you seen it?
我放了威化饼在这儿  是不是你拿了
I left a Belgian waffle out here. Did you take it?
-没有  -你怎会放威化饼在走廊
-No. - Why'd you leave it in the hall?
我还不想吃
I wasn't ready for it.
回到正题  你有看见猴子吗
The monkey. Have you seen a monkey?
我见过吉斯·菲尔宾
I saw Regis Philbin once.
谢谢你  哈克斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Heckles.
你们欠我威化饼
You owe me a waffle.
他是一只白脸的黑卷尾猴
He's a black capuchin monkey with a white face...
加俄国酱外加腌黄瓜
...with Russian dressing and pickles on the side.
好  谢谢
Ok. Thanks.
今天过得如何
How did it go today?
很好啊  不错  真的很不错
Oh, great! It went great. Really great.
那是酒吗
Is that wine?
对  想喝吗
Yeah. You want some?
我非常乐意来点
Oh, I would love some.
可你知道吗  我们别在这儿喝
But y'know what? Y'know what? But let's not drink it here.
我兴致不错  我们去纽华克市好吗
I'm feeling kind of crazy. You wanna go to Newark?
行啊  去就去呗
Okay, we can do that.
但是我们前往这东北犯罪之都前
but before we head off to the murder capital of the Northeast...
我有些话想对你说
... I kind of wanted to run something by you.
还记得吗  我们曾谈过...
You know how we were talking before...
感情...之类的问题
...about relationships, and stuff.
天啊  罗斯  我装不下去了
Oh, God, Ross, I cannot do this!
好吧  一口回绝  太伤人了
Okay, quick and painful.
上帝啊
Oh, God!
好吧  我说了  豁出去了
Okay, all right. All right, okay.
罗斯  别恨我
Ross. Please don't hate me.
到底是什么
What?
-你知道马塞尔吧...  -怎么
- You know Marcel? - Well?
我好像...好像把他弄丢了
I kind of... kind of lost him.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
我唯一的要求就是别让他跑出去
All I asked you to do was keep him in here!
我知道  对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
不  我该负一半的责任
No, you know what? It's partially my fault.
我就不该叫你照顾猴子练手
I shouldn't have had you start with a monkey.
应该要你从照顾钢笔铅笔开始才对
I should've started you off with like a pen or a pencil.
罗斯  我已尽最大的努力
Ross, I'm doing everything I can.
我已叫大家分头去找还有...
I got everyone's looking for him and I got
-是谁  -动物控制中心
- Who is it? - Animal Control.
瞧  我甚至打给动物控制中心
I've even got Animal Control.
你打给动物控制中心
You called Animal Control?
是啊  怎么了  你不喜欢他们
Why? Do you not like them?
马塞尔是非法的外来动物
Marcel is an illegal exotic animal.
我无权在市内饲养他
I'm not allowed to have him in the city.
万一被他们找到  他们就会带走他
If they find him, they'll take him away from me.
好吧  可是  你从来没告诉过我们
Well, now, see, you never ever told us that.
没错  因为我没想到
That' right. Because I never expected you
你会请他们来家里
to invite them to the apartment!
嗨  谢谢你来
Hi. Thanks for coming.
有人遗失猴子吗
Somebody called about a monkey?
你知道吗  这完全是个误会
You know, that was a complete misunderstanding.
我以为我们有养猴子  但是我们没有
We thought we had a monkey, but we didn't.
-结果是个帽子  -猫崽
- Turned out it was a hat. - Cat!
我们查遍了三楼四楼  没人看到马塞尔
Hi. We checked the third and fourth floor, no-one's seen Marcel.
-马塞尔  -我叔叔马塞尔
- Marcel? - My uncle Marcel.
那猴子是以你叔叔命名的吗
ls that who the monkey's named after?
你知道持有非法外来动物
Oookay. Are you aware that possession of an illegal exotic is
可判刑两年
uh, punishable by up to two years in prison
并没收动物吗
and confiscation of the animal?
天啊
Oh, my God!
你要把这可怜的小东西关进监牢
You'd put that poor little creature in jail?
菲比  你记得我们谈过
Pheebs. Remember how we talked about
说话前先自己默念一遍吗
saying things quietly to yourself first?
记得  但总没有时间
Yes, but there isn't always time.
我相信我们能以友善的方式处理  请坐
I'm sure there's some friendly way to reconcile this. Have a seat.
首先  我们还没互相认识
First of all, we haven't been introduced,
我叫莫妮卡·盖勒
I'm Monica Geller.
天啊  你是莫妮卡
Oh, my God, you are!
-而你是瑞秋·格林对吗  -是我
- And you're Rachel Greene! -Yeah.
我是露易莎·珍妮提  林肯高中校友
Luisa Gianetti! Lincoln High?
年级教室里我坐在你们后面
I sat behind you guys in homeroom.
露易莎  天哪
Luisa! Oh, my God!
莫妮卡  是露易莎
Monica! It's Luisa!
-一个教室的露易莎  -正是
- The Luisa from home room! - Yes.
你们根本不知道我是谁  对不
You have no idea who I am, do you?
-不  -一点也不
- No. - Not at all.
或许是因为你们那四年都当我不存在
Well, maybe that's because you spent four years ignoring me.
说一句"早安  露易莎"有那么难吗
Would it have been hard to say, "Morning,Luisa"...
或是"好漂亮的连身裤"
...or "Nice overalls"?
对不起
Oh, I'm so sorry!
我不怪你  你当时很胖
It's not so much you. You were fat.
你有自己的烦恼
You had your own problems.
可你实在是个贱货
But you. What a bitch!
什么
What?
这样吧  别计较了
You know what? Be that as it may...
猴子的事情你能帮我们吗  念念旧情
...could you help us with the monkey thing, for old times'sake?
加油  山猫队
Go, Bobcats!
我可以  但我拒绝
I could. But I won't.
如果我找到猴子  他就是我的了
If I find that monkey, he's mine.
抱歉
Sorry.
马塞尔
Marcel?
需要帮忙吗
Hi, can I help you?
我们有急事  我们在找东西
We're having an emergency, and we were looking for something.
-一只猴子  -对  你有看见吗
- A monkey. - Yes, have you seen any?
不  我没看见猴子
No, I haven't seen a monkey.
你知道如何修理散热器吗
Can you fix radiators?
当然  你试过将转钮转回去吗
Sure! Did you try turning the knob back the other way?
-当然  -那我就不知道了
- Of course! - Oh. Then, no.
-尝尝  是不是兰姆酒加多了  -等等
- Taste this. Is there too much rum in here? - Just a second.
-希望你们能找到猴子  -不  等等
- Hope you find your monkey. - No,wait!
我们对散热器或许不太懂
We may not know about radiators...
我们可是冷暖环境控制的专家
... but we do have expertise in the heating and cooling milieu.
我们不是正在忙吗
Aren't we in the middle of something?
对  但这两位女士热得冒烟
Yes, But these women are very hot,
而且需要我们的帮助
and they need our help.
而且还很火辣
And they're very hot!
我们不行
We can't, all right?
抱歉
We're sorry.
你们不知道我们有多抱歉
You don't know how sorry.
我们答应人家要找猴子
We promised to find this monkey.
如果你们看到他 他大约这么高  名叫马塞尔
If you see him, he's about yea high and answers to the name Marcel
如果能拥有你们的照片  就算帮了大忙
So if we could get pictures of you, it'd help us out.
从现在起  不准你和其他人讲话
From now on, you don't get to talk to other people.
-马塞尔  -马塞尔
- Marcel.  - Marcel.
-我的天  -什么
- Oh, my God! - What?
有东西碰到我的右腿
Something brushed up against my right leg.
-是什么  -没什么  是我的左腿
- What is it? - Oh, it's okay. It was just my left leg.
看  菲比
Look, Phoebe!
马塞尔  过来
Oh, Marcel! Come here!
闪开  两位小姐
Step aside, ladies.
-你要干什么  -打镇定剂
- What are you gonna do? - Just a tranquilizer.
快跑  马塞尔  快跑
Run, Marcel, run!
坏了
Damn!
-你还好吧  -还行
- Are you okay? - I think so.
糟了
Oh, gosh!
-马塞尔  -马塞尔
- Marcel. - Marcel.
太荒谬了  我们问遍了这一带
oh, this is ridiculous! We've been all over the neighbourhood.
他不见了  就这么消失了
He's gone, he's-he's just gone.
-罗斯  还不一定  -拜托  又冷又黑
-Ross, you don't know that. - It's cold, it's dark.
他根本不认识路
He doesn't know the Village!
现在我的脚又受伤了
And now I have a broken foot.
猴子没了脚又受伤
I have no monkey and a broken foot!
真的感谢你
Thank you very much!
罗斯  我已向你道歉过无数次
Ross, you know, I've said I'm sorry a million times.
你到底要我怎么样
What do you want me to do?
你要我的脚也受伤吗  我现在就来
You want me to break my foot too? I'll break it right now.
疼死了  这下你高兴了吧
Oh, my God! There, are you happy now?
对  你踢完路标后
Yeah, now that you kicked the sign...
我突然不再想念马塞尔了
... I don't miss Marcel anymore!
我真的不是故意的
It's not like I did this on purpose.
当然  这是典型的瑞秋作风
No, this is just vintage Rachel.
这种事常发生在你身上
Things just sort of happen around you!
你活在瑞秋的世界中  做着瑞秋的事情
You're off in "Rachel Land," doing your "Rachel Thing"...
完全无视别人的猴子
...total oblivious to people's monkeys
或是别人的感觉
or to people's feelings and
-罗斯  -我不想听  就这么忘了吧
- Ross. - I don't want to hear it! Forget it, okay?
-罗斯  -干嘛
- Ross! - What?
喂  香蕉男
Hey, banana man!
这下可好
This is so intense!
一边的屁股在睡觉  另一边却毫不知情
One side of my butt is totally asleep and the other side has no idea.
你有订香蕉吗
Hi! Did you order some bananas?
-那是干吗的  -还我的猴子
- What about it? - Give me my monkey back!
-我没猴子  -那干嘛买一箱香蕉
- I don't have a monkey. - Then what's with the bananas?
补充钾
Potassium.
马塞尔  马塞尔  快说  他在哪儿
Marcel! Marcel! Okay, where is he?
马塞尔  马塞尔
Marcel! Marcel!
马塞尔
Marcel.
你对他干了什么
What have you done to him?
这是我的猴子  叫佩蒂
That's my monkey. That's Patty.
你疯了不成  过来  马塞尔
Are you insane? Come here, Marcel.
过来  佩蒂
Come here, Patty.
过来  马塞尔
Come here, Marcel.
过来  佩蒂
Come here, Patty.
过来  小猴子
Here, monkey.
过来  小猴子 逮到你了
Here, monkey! Gotcha!
-把我的猴子还给我  -那是我的
- Give me my monkey back! - It's mine.
你们到法官面前去争吧
You're both gonna have to take this up with the judge.
那不是我的猴子 只有衣服是我的
That's not my monkey. The dress is mine.
你随时可以送回来
You can send it back whenever.
-好吧  我要我的猴子  -不成
- All right, I want my monkey! - No!
-露易莎  拜托了  -抱歉了  舞会皇后
- Oh, come on, Luisa. - Sorry, prom queen.
你高中干嘛那么贱  为何不当个胖妞
You had to be a bitch in high school, you couldn't've been fat.
高中那会  我是舞会皇后
In high school, I was prom queen...
和返校节皇后  但是你
...and the homecoming queen and you...
你也在的啊
...were also there.
如果你把猴子带走
If you take this monkey,
我将失去我生命中重要的人
I'll lose an important person in my life.
你可以尽情恨我  但请别折磨他
You can hate me if you want, but please do not punish him.
别这样  露易莎
Come on, Luisa.
此时你有机会做一个宽容的人
You have a chance to be the bigger person here.
把握机会吧
Take it!
不
No.
那么  我只好告诉你的长官
All right. Then I'll call your supervisor and tell her...
你在我朋友的屁股上开了一枪
...you shot my friend with a dart!
把这件衣服脱掉多好  是不是
It'll be nice to get this off, won't it?
或是这样穿着也不错
Or we can leave it on. That's fine.
配上合适的女鞋  就是完美的一套了
With the right pumps, that would be a great little outfit.
抱歉  我之前对你这么凶
Listen, I'm sorry I was so hard on you before
不  罗斯  都是我的错  我差点弄丢
No, Ross, come in, it was my fault. I almost lost your
是啊  但他也是你找回来的  你真厉害
Yeah, but you got him back. You were great.
那瓶酒还在
We still have that bottle of wine.
有心情喝杯葡萄酒吗
Are you in the mood for something grape?
-好呀  -很好
- Sure, that would be good. - All right.
隔壁一定在用吸尘器
The neighbors must be vacuuming.
只要我们在这儿就成
Well, as long as we're here...
不谈那个话题
...and not on the subject....
我在想
I was thinking about...
我们刚刚实在是恶言相向
... how mad we got at each other before.
大概是因为我们太
And maybe it was partially because of how we
-瑞秋  -巴瑞
- Rachel? - Barry?
我办不到  我无法和明蒂结婚
I can't do it. I can't marry Mindy.
我想我爱的人依然是你
I think I'm still in love with you.
我们一定得开始锁门了
We have got to start locking that door!
这是我参演《音乐之声》
This is me in The Sound of Music.
-看到冯·特拉普家的孩子们没  -没
- See the von Trapp kids? - No.
那是因为我在他们前面
That's because I'm in front of them.
我以为那是阿尔卑斯山
I thought that was an alp.
我的高中时代并不如意
High school wasn't my favorite time.
说不准  我爱高中
I don't know. I loved high school.
四年的舞会  约会和做爱
It was four years of parties, dating and sex and
我和400个男孩上的住宿学校
Well, I went to boarding school with 400 boys.
每次做爱都是一次生活方式的重大抉择
Any sex I had would've involved a major lifestyle choice.
那不是回到一百万年前
Doesn't it seem like a million years ago?
我的屁股蛋儿醒了
My butt cheek is waking up!